cookpolitical.com 2010-11-21

# Privacy Policy | The Cook Political Report

_Effective June 2008_

### Our Commitment To Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. 

To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. 

### The Information We Collect

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on _The Cook Political Report_ Web site. 

_The Cook Political Report_ may track and record certain nonpersonal information of Site users, including IP address, operating system, type of browser, referring URL, and time spent on the Site in order to gain aggregate data that may be analyzed for trends and statistics on how our visitors use the Site.

_The Cook Political Report_ may use accumulated aggregate non-personal data for several purposes including, but not limited to, Site traffic analysis, evaluation of Cook Political’s services, and program planning. _The Cook Political Report_ may use a third-party Web site analytics provider to track and record nonpersonal information of Site users and provide reports based on such information to The Cook Political Report. Such providers may use that nonpersonal information for their internal purposes.

We collect personal data, including financial data, in order to process subscriptions to this Site. The types of personal information we collect during the subscription process includes:

  * Name
  * Address
  * E-mail address
  * Phone number
  * Credit/Debit Card Information

The subscription process is optional and occurs in several steps. During the first steps, you will provide your name and contact information, plus the names and zip codes of additional users if you are subscribing a group. All information collected will be encrypted by our secure server. In the final step, your Web browser will be directed to Google in order to process a credit card transaction. This data is collected outside of our server, and Google is responsible for ensuring the security of the data.

If you do not wish to become a subscriber using this online process, you may contact us to arrange an alternate way to process your transaction.

You may cancel your subscription within one week of processing the transaction. To do this, you must contact us in writing within seven days of the start of your subscription.

No user is required to complete the subscription process or provide us with any personal information. However, non-subscribers will not have access to premium content.

### The Way We Use Information

We use the information you provide about yourself when processing your subscription only to complete the transaction. We do not share this information with outside parties other than Google except to the extent necessary to complete that order. 

We use your e-mail address to send you a weekly e-newsletter update, which is usually sent on Thursdays. We may also send you “alerts” with breaking-news style content on occasion.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our Web site and develop content. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. 

### Our Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Nevertheless, no transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### Cookies

_The Cook Political Report_ employs "cookies" to provide visitors with tailored information to facilitate your use of the Site. A "cookie" is an element of data that a Web site sends to a visitor's browser which, in turn, may store that element on the visitor's hard drive or memory. Any cookies sent by the Site will be marked so that they will be accessible only by the Site. A visitor may block or delete our cookies from the hard drive. However, by disabling cookies, certain Site features and functionality may no longer work properly, or at all. 

### Links with Other Sites

The Site contains links to other Web sites that are owned or controlled by third parties. Please note that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from those of the Site. _The Cook Political Report_ is not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of any linked Web site. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of any Web site you wish to visit before disclosing any information. 

### Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our Web site from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our Web site is structured to attract anyone under 13. 

If a child under age 13 sends us an e-mail with a question or comment, and we are aware of the child's age, we will write back using that e-mail address but we will not keep the e-mail address or use it again.

### How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by logging into the site and clicking on the “My Account” link. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. This includes asking you to provide your username and password. 

If you forget your password, you can enter your username or e-mail address on record on the “Request new password” page ([http://www.cookpolitical com/user/password](http://www.cookpolitical%20com/user/password)). The site will send you via e-mail a link that can be used one time to reset your password. 

Alternatively, you can contact us at the e-mail address listed above, and we will provide assistance.

### Location of Servers and Transfer of Information

Our servers are located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using our Site or providing your personal information to us, you consent to this transfer and to the collection, storage, processing and use of your personal information in the United States. In addition, our service providers may not be located in your geographic area in the United States. By providing your personal information on the Site, you also consent to the transfer of your data to these service providers.

### How to Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please call us at (202) 739-8525 or send us an e-mail at [cookpoliticalreport@cookpolitical.com](mailto:cookpoliticalreport@cookpolitical.com).
